<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moderate to Tough on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/tags/moderate-to-tough/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Moderate to Tough on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/moderate-to-tough/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separating the Brahmaputra valley of Assam from the plains of Bangladesh lies hilly Meghalaya (‘the abode of clouds’). The state’s population predominantly comprises the Jaintia, Khasi and Garo tribal groups, who live in the eastern, central and western parts respectively. Geographically, Meghalaya is the first hill range that the rain baring monsoon clouds hit after crossing peninsular India and the Bay of Bengal.  Mawsynram and Cherrapunjee (Sohra) set on dramatic horseshoes of rocky cliffs receive some of the highest rainfall on earth, creating very impressive waterfalls and carving out some of Asia’s longest caves. Meghalaya’s tribal groups also maintain their matrilineal system, with property and names passed down from mother to daughter, and men moving in with their maternal in-laws after marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this tour we explore the best of the Khasi and Jaintia hills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Sikkim &amp; West Bengal</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-sikkim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-sikkim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sikkim, bordering Tibet in the north and northeast, Bhutan in the east, Nepal in the west, and West Bengal in the south is a mountanious state. Sikkim was its own mountain kingdom till 1975 and still retains a very distinctive personality. The meditative, mural-filled traditional monasteries of Tibetan Buddhism coexist with Hindu shrines of the ever-growing Nepali community, with both religions creating some astonishing latter-day megasculptures to adorn the skyline.Clean, green and &amp;lsquo;all organic&amp;rsquo; since 2016, Sikkim is mostly a maze of plunging, supersteep valleys thick with lush subtropical woodlands and rhododendron groves, rising in the north to the spectacular white-top peaks of the eastern Himalaya. When clouds clear, an ever-thrilling experience from many a ridge-top perch is spotting the world&amp;rsquo;s third-highest mountain, Khangchendzonga (8598m), on the northwestern dawn horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular tour takes you from Darjeeling in west bengal to the south and western districts to sikkim.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>