<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Treks &amp; Walks on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/categories/treks-walks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Treks &amp; Walks on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/treks-walks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Holiday in Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/walking-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/walking-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separating the Brahmaputra valley of Assam from the plains of Bangladesh lies hilly Meghalaya (‘the abode of clouds’). The state’s population predominantly comprises the Jaintia, Khasi and Garo tribal groups, who live in the eastern, central and western parts respectively. Geographically, Meghalaya is the first hill range that the rain baring monsoon clouds hit after crossing peninsular India and the Bay of Bengal.  Mawsynram and Cherrapunjee (Sohra) set on dramatic horseshoes of rocky cliffs receive some of the highest rainfall on earth, creating very impressive waterfalls and carving out some of Asia’s longest caves. Meghalaya’s tribal groups also maintain their matrilineal system, with property and names passed down from mother to daughter, and men moving in with their maternal in-laws after marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tour includes full day hikes and short walks to some of the best destination of the state. From historic trade routes to the natural wonders of bioengineering, sweeping panoramas of the Blangladeshi plains and its neighboring hills to deep valleys and canyons, through quaint remote villages and small local markets, we take you on a journey across this little known land.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Holiday in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/walking-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/walking-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arunachal Pradesh, ‘the dawn lit Mountains’ is the easternmost state of India. This tour is based in the eastern part of Arunachal Pradesh close to the Myanmar and Chinese frontiers, a maze of greenery and home to a vibrant mix of cultures. This is the land where three giant river valleys come down and meet the plains, hence giving birth to the mighty Brahmaputra. Home to the earliest tea producers of the subcontinent, some of the earliest oil finds of the world and a string of vibrant wildlife parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour includes a series of walks across these eastern most river valleys. This is a land of the Animist and Theravada Buddhist tribes of the state who are still very rooted in their culture and traditions. You will be walking through wildlife sanctuaries, camp next to pristine lakes, visit idellic villages, indulging in local cuisines and have authentic interactions with the people who live here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour is quite flexible and can be worked out around the duration that you have in hand. Do write in to us for the details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rainforest Trek in Eastern Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/rainforest-trek-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/rainforest-trek-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trekking holiday takes you to the Namdapha National Park located in eastern Arunachal Pradesh. Namdapha is one of the largest protected areas of Asia as well as the northernmost lowland evergreen rainforest of the world. We take you walking for 5 days through thick rain forest, grasslands and riverine areas of the national park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perched between the East Himalayan and the Indo-Burmese Biodiversity hotspots Namdapha is home to over 1000 species of plants, 425 avian species and over 90 species of mammals. This is also the only wildlife park to host four big cats in India, namely the Royal Bengal Tiger, Spotted Leopard, Snow Leopard and the Clouded Leopard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tour takes you far from the hustle bustle of daily life and deep into inarguably the wildest region of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trekking in Sikkim and Bengal</title>
      <link>/tours/trekking-sikkim-and-bengal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/trekking-sikkim-and-bengal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trek takes you to the hills of Sikkim and North Bengal, a mystical land of abundant natural beauty with verdant forests, quaint sub alpine villages and high towering mountains. Sikkim is home to the magnificant Kanchanjunga Massif, the third-highest mountain on earth. The pinnacle of this majestic mountain is perennially snowcapped and ever towering over the region like the deity that she is. The trek will take you across state and sometimes national borders, as we make our way south from the Barsey Rhodondren Sanctuary along the Nepalese frontier, walking the phenominal Singalila Ridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This region is perched between the giant plains of the Gangetic and Brahmaputra valleys and the high Himalayan massif. Barsey Rhododendron Sanctuary spans over the razor sharp Singalila Range which forms the border wall between India and Nepal. Ranging from an altitude of about 7000 to 14000 feet, the flora of the sanctuary ranges from broadleaf and coniferous forests to alpine meadows, but the queen of this sanctuary is the Rhodendron of which over 600 kinds can be found here itself. The route takes us from a starting altitude of about 2700 mts up to about 3750 mts. The Singalila ridge, which is about 50 kms long offers phenominal panoramas of the valleys of Nepal and Sikkim, and the high peaks of Himalayas especially the sights of 5 out of the 6 highest peaks on earth. The mornings and evenight offer spellbinding vistas, almost an amphitheatre where we are the spectators and the high peaks the protagonists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trek can be quite flexible in duration without losing its charms. Please write in to us with your ideal duration and we will get back with an appropriate itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trekking in Western Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/trekking-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/trekking-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular trek is set in Western Arunachal Pradesh, in the states Buddhist belt close to the tri-junction between India, Tibet and Bhutan. This region is home to the Monpa, Sherdukpen and the Brokpa people. Starting from the township of Dirang, the trek takes you along the Bhutanese border via a region known for its high altitude lakes and rhodendrons while ending in the Sela Pass or Jang depending on the duration one chooses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This region is known as the eastern gateway to Tibet, an age old trading route between India, Bhutan and Tibet. In the duration of tour you will visit and experience some of the important places and aspects of this region such as spotting the River Dolphins of the Brahmaputra, visit the Tawang Monastry, Bum la pass and the orchidarium at Tipi among others. During the trek you will pass through remote settlements of the Brokpa (the yak and sheep herders) and the Monpa tribes , getting to interact and first hand window into their way of life. The trek starts from the sub-alpine forests at about 1500 mts and takes you up beyond the treeline reaching about 4200 mts. The trek takes of through forests of Rhodendrons in a typical Himalayan setting offering views of the high peaks of the Bhutan and Arunachal Himalayas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>