<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multi-Activity on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/categories/multi-activity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Multi-Activity on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/multi-activity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Activity holiday in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/multiactivity-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/multiactivity-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This multi-activity tour of eastern Arunachal Pradesh takes us on bicycles, rafts and on foot across the watershed area of the Brahmaputra River valley. This region situated at the foothills of the Mishmi hills the eastern flank to the Himalayan chain, is the land of the Animist and Theravada Buddhist tribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authentic interactions, local cuisine, history and lifestyle of the tribes etc are our focus here. The cycling phase takes us across territories of six different tribes where as the hiking phase takes us away from civilization into two different and unique wildlife sanctuaries. This multi-activity tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh also includes rafting on the Dibang and the Lohit rivers, the easternmost tributaries of the Brahmaputra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Activity holiday in Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/multiactivity-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/multiactivity-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular Multi-activity tour takes us on bicycles and on foot across the Khasi and Jaintia Hills of Meghalaya. Due to its unique georgaphical location, it some of the highest rain fall on earth which in turn bestows this region with its amazing mix of forested valleys and grassland plateaus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cycling phase takes you across the beautiful landscape, whereas the hiking days take you through some of the best trails of the region, amongst which the famous living root bridges trail. Enroute we will picnic lunch in beautiful locations and swim in prestine pools while visitng waterfalls, caves and local archery competitions. During this multi activity tour of Meghalaya tour you will stay in quaint homestays, off the grid farms and small family run establishments. The tour will give you indepth and personal prospective of this land and its wonderful people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour is quite flexible, we can mould the entire proceeding looking at your preferences and abilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Activity holiday in Assam</title>
      <link>/tours/multiactivity-tour-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/multiactivity-tour-assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This multi-activity tour takes us to the Brahmaputra valley of Assam. A lush strip of land sandwiched between the Himalayan landmass on the north and the lesser hills of Nagaland and Meghalaya in the south. The Brahmaputra valley is home to a multitude of ethinicities, a string of wildlife sanctuaries and the famous Assam tea among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this tour we will indulge in short day cycling and hiking forays. Explore the culture and cuisine of this land, embark on wildlife safari’s, live in and learn about life in a typical Assamese Tea Plantation, spot the endangered River Dolphins of the Brahmaputra, cycle around the largest river island of the world and much more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>