<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family Adventure on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/categories/family-adventure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family Adventure on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/family-adventure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Family holiday in Assam</title>
      <link>/tours/family-holiday-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/family-holiday-assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setting for this family holiday is the lush Brahmaputra valley of Assam. This is the physical heart of Northeastern India. A vast valley spread between the mighty Himalayas in the North and the lesser hills of Meghalaya and Nagaland in the South. Assam is the largest and most accessible of the Northeastern States. This fertile land is generally known for its rich wildlife parks, lush tea plantations and unique cultures. On this tour we will explore, experience and observe some of the best that this state has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This holiday can be tailored to your family’s personal preferences, be it the range of activities, duration or accommodation options. This trips can be guided, unguided , driver driven or selfdriven depending on your preference and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family holiday Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/family-holiday-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/family-holiday-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This active holiday for the family is set in hilly Meghalaya. Meghalaya literally meaning the ‘Abode of clouds’ is one of the wettest places on earth during the monsoons. Cherrapunji and Mawsynram both in Meghalaya take their turn recording some of the heaviest rainfall on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this tour of Meghalaya you will be travelling through the west Khasi and neighbouring Jaintia hills overlooking the plains of Bangladesh. Deep forested valleys, gushing rivers, innumerable waterfalls, natural root bridges, archery competitions, village markets etc will be the common sights. Short hikes, water based activities,Ziplines, caves and waterfall visits are in the cards on this tour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This holiday can be tailored to your family’s personal preferences, be it the range of activities, duration or accommodation options. This trip can be driver driven or selfdriven depending on your preference and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family holiday in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/family-holiday-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/family-holiday-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This active family holiday of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh is set in some of the only flatlands of the state lying at the foothills of the Mishmi Hills (Himalayas eastern flank). Exploring around the Brahmaputra, Lohit and Dibang rivers. Rich plains have always given rise to more sophisticated and elaborate societies. This is the region where Hinduism, Theravada Buddhism and the Animist tribes meet and have coexisted for eons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the duration of this tour you will get an in-depth into this interesting regions wide mix of cultures, experience the lush environment and bio-diversity, indulge in some adventures and learn about the rich history of this little known corner of the sub-continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This holiday can be tailored to your family’s personal preferences, be it the range of activities, duration or accommodation options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>