<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tough on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/tags/tough/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tough on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tough/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overland Tour of 4 states NE India </title>
      <link>/tours/motorcycle-tour-northeast-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/motorcycle-tour-northeast-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular ride takes us through the backroads of some of India’s easternmost states namely Arunachal Pradesh, Nagaland, Assam and Meghalaya. A rider’s delight, this route includes the dense forested hills of Nagaland, and Arunachal Pradesh, the tea oil rich regions of Assam and the wettest places on Earth at Meghalaya. Incidentally this region has one of the highest densities of ethnicities and languages in the whole of India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the tour we ride through territories of tribes such as the Nyshi, Apatani, Tagin, Galo, Adi, Idu Mishmi, Digaru Mishmi, Miju Mishmi, Singpho, Khamti, Konyak, Ao, Lotha, Angami, Karbi, Dimasa, Jaintia and Khasi to name a few. Infact every single day takes us through territories of different tribes, each tribe totally different from the previous. You will ride across swathes of lush tea plantations, some of the oldest oil fields on earth, some of the greatest wildlife sanctuaries of the sub-continent, the largest river island on earth, quaint and remote villages, orange orchards, unending forests, view some of the tallest waterfalls and visit some of the deepest caves of Asia among others. The loop starts and ends at Guwahati, which is the capital of Assam and the largest city among the seven states. The ride itself takes us through varying terrain, road conditions and vegetation, every single day bringing totally new and unique settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of the Mishmi Hills</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tours-mishmi-hills-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tours-mishmi-hills-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mishmi Hills is a southward extension of eastern most parts of the Great Himalayan Mountain Range - its high northern and eastern reaches touching China, whereas its southern parts fanning into the tropical forests of southwest China and Myanmar. On this tour we foray into the Dibang Valley district, named after the Dibang River - one of the key tributaries of the Brahmaputra. The Dibang originates in China and flows through the length of the valley in a north-south direction. Other river systems that flow through the area include the Ithun, Ason, Chipu, Aba, Iphi, Sisiri, Datung, and the Deopani River.
The Dibang Valley district is divided into Lower and Upper Dibang Valley. ). In between the start and the end, one will traverse across varied landscape, terrain, road conditions and meet the all important tribes of this region. From the Oil and Tea growing regions of Assam, the tropical forests of Namdapha and Kamlang to the cane and grasslands of the Acheso valley, everyday is a revelation. Interestingly during the entire ride you will cross territories of the Chakma, Singpho, Khamti, Miju Mishmi, Digaru Mishmi and finally the Idu Mishmi tribes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Western Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-western-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-western-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cycle tour of Arunachal Pradesh takes you all the way to the end of the road close to the tri-Juncture of Bhutan, Tibet and India. The setting of this ride is in western Arunachal Pradesh, the Buddhist belt of the state. This is one of the highest motorable routes of the eastern bit of the Himalayas, at places taking you to an altitude of 4200mts. The road condition though not at the best is still better than most parts of Arunachal Pradesh. The route takes you riding along the Bhutan border on little used roads. Slush, mud, broken roads steep inclines, long downhills, snow etc are all parts of this ride.The cycling phase covers between 300 to 650 Kms depending on the duration you choose, for most parts riding on little used backroads of this region historically known as the Monyul. Incidentally, in a rough manner we mirror the same route the Dalai Lama used in his exodus from Tibet in the year 1959.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>