<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>River Trip on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/categories/river-trip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in River Trip on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/river-trip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>River Journey on the Brahmaputra</title>
      <link>/tours/river-trip-northeast-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/river-trip-northeast-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This river journey takes you to eastern Arunachal Pradesh and Upper Assam. Starting right from the mouth of the Brahmaputra Valley we meander down the Dibang river into the mighty Brahmaputra. This is a land surrounded by the mighty Himalayas and its lesser hill ranges on three sides and a myriad of rivers snaking west to form the only male river of India, The Brahmaputra. Over the duration of the tour you will raft and kayak down the swift flows of the Dibang to the more leisurely pace of the Brahmaputra, all the while having the options of Tubing, Body boarding, Snorkelling and Angling. Overnights will be spent camping in beautiful and secluded locations offering some of the most phenomenal sunsets. All meals will be freshly cooked and hot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflatable Kayaks (aka ‘Duckies’ or IKs) are perfect for adventure seekers. It offer the sensation of kayaking with better stability than a hard shell kayak. These boats are easy to paddle and manoeuvre, making them a great choice for novice to expert paddlers. Guides paddling their own inflatable kayaks will help teach you the basics and then lead you “follow-the-leader” style through the sections. If you should fall out: no problem; the guides will be right there to pick you up. It’s all part of the fun. So, the question is: are you a “do-it-yourselfer”? Looking for a little more adventure? Well here is your chance to sit above the flow and power your way down through the river on your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trip is not about big white water, it’s a more relaxed trip. Though in the first two days you will encounter a series of class 1 &amp;amp; 2 rapids, its generally all relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>