<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meghalaya on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/tags/meghalaya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meghalaya on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/meghalaya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Holiday in Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/walking-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/walking-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separating the Brahmaputra valley of Assam from the plains of Bangladesh lies hilly Meghalaya (‘the abode of clouds’). The state’s population predominantly comprises the Jaintia, Khasi and Garo tribal groups, who live in the eastern, central and western parts respectively. Geographically, Meghalaya is the first hill range that the rain baring monsoon clouds hit after crossing peninsular India and the Bay of Bengal.  Mawsynram and Cherrapunjee (Sohra) set on dramatic horseshoes of rocky cliffs receive some of the highest rainfall on earth, creating very impressive waterfalls and carving out some of Asia’s longest caves. Meghalaya’s tribal groups also maintain their matrilineal system, with property and names passed down from mother to daughter, and men moving in with their maternal in-laws after marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tour includes full day hikes and short walks to some of the best destination of the state. From historic trade routes to the natural wonders of bioengineering, sweeping panoramas of the Blangladeshi plains and its neighboring hills to deep valleys and canyons, through quaint remote villages and small local markets, we take you on a journey across this little known land.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family holiday Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/family-holiday-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/family-holiday-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This active holiday for the family is set in hilly Meghalaya. Meghalaya literally meaning the ‘Abode of clouds’ is one of the wettest places on earth during the monsoons. Cherrapunji and Mawsynram both in Meghalaya take their turn recording some of the heaviest rainfall on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this tour of Meghalaya you will be travelling through the west Khasi and neighbouring Jaintia hills overlooking the plains of Bangladesh. Deep forested valleys, gushing rivers, innumerable waterfalls, natural root bridges, archery competitions, village markets etc will be the common sights. Short hikes, water based activities,Ziplines, caves and waterfall visits are in the cards on this tour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This holiday can be tailored to your family’s personal preferences, be it the range of activities, duration or accommodation options. This trip can be driver driven or selfdriven depending on your preference and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Activity holiday in Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/multiactivity-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/multiactivity-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular Multi-activity tour takes us on bicycles and on foot across the Khasi and Jaintia Hills of Meghalaya. Due to its unique georgaphical location, it some of the highest rain fall on earth which in turn bestows this region with its amazing mix of forested valleys and grassland plateaus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cycling phase takes you across the beautiful landscape, whereas the hiking days take you through some of the best trails of the region, amongst which the famous living root bridges trail. Enroute we will picnic lunch in beautiful locations and swim in prestine pools while visitng waterfalls, caves and local archery competitions. During this multi activity tour of Meghalaya tour you will stay in quaint homestays, off the grid farms and small family run establishments. The tour will give you indepth and personal prospective of this land and its wonderful people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour is quite flexible, we can mould the entire proceeding looking at your preferences and abilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overland Tour of Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from Guwahati the capital of Assam, this motorcycle / overland tour takes you through little known secluded roads of Meghalaya. Entering Meghalaya in the western end we make our way to its far eastern hills, enroute traversing through varying conditions and basking in the vistas of the Meghalayan hills and the plains of Bangladesh while staying in charming locations all through settled by different tribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a land of plaetues, hills and deep river valleys. Richly endowned by nature with some of the deepest caves and tallest waterfalls of Asia. Almost every day you come across numerous waterfalls which depending on tour time of travel could vary from gushing frothy to a subtle glassy appearance. Depending on the duration you have the itinerary can include some cave exploration and canyoning in one of the longest caves of the world. We will take time to visit of the natural root bridges of the state including the most famous double decker bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route is quite flexible depending the duration you have in hand, level of involvement you want to put in or your techical ability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separating the Brahmaputra valley of Assam from the plains of Bangladesh lies hilly Meghalaya (‘the abode of clouds’). The state’s population predominantly comprises the Jaintia, Khasi and Garo tribal groups, who live in the eastern, central and western parts respectively. Geographically, Meghalaya is the first hill range that the rain baring monsoon clouds hit after crossing peninsular India and the Bay of Bengal.  Mawsynram and Cherrapunjee (Sohra) set on dramatic horseshoes of rocky cliffs receive some of the highest rainfall on earth, creating very impressive waterfalls and carving out some of Asia’s longest caves. Meghalaya’s tribal groups also maintain their matrilineal system, with property and names passed down from mother to daughter, and men moving in with their maternal in-laws after marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this tour we explore the best of the Khasi and Jaintia hills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>