<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cycling on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/categories/cycling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cycling on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/cycling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Assam</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stretching 600km along the Brahmaputra River Valley, Assam is the largest and most accessible of the Northeast States. Well known for its national parks abounding in rhinoceroses, elephants, deer and primates (with respectable tiger numbers too), more than 3000sq km of lush tea plantations and a vibrant mix of cultures, it welcomes visitors with a subtly flavored cuisine and a hospitable population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cycle tour of Assam takes you on both the banks of central Brahmaputra Valley, giving you experiences of living in tea plantations, indulging in wildlife spotting, experiencing its rich cuisine while cycling through lush and pleasant surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-eastern-arunachal_pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-eastern-arunachal_pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cycle tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh (the eastern most state of India) takes you to the watershed of the mighty Brahmaputra River.  India’s wildest and least explored state, Arunachal (literally the ‘land of dawn-lit mountains’) rises abruptly from the Assam plains as a mass of densely forested and impossibly steep hills, culminating in snowcapped peaks along the Tibetan border. This state is home to 26 major tribes with over 100 sub-tribes and clans speaking some 50 odd dialects. Arunachal is perhaps the last sanctuary for India’s natural and anthropological heritage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular part of Arunachal Pradesh is where the three easternmost tributaries come together to form one of the mightiest river valleys of the world. Surrounded by the Himalayas and the Patkai Range on three sides and Brahmaputra valley on the other, this region is the home of numerous tribal cultures. Each one of these tribes are unique in their language, food, textile pattern, headgear, machetes etc, yet so distinct with strong Mongoloid features, tight knit society, and their nonchalant ease in and around the forests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separating the Brahmaputra valley of Assam from the plains of Bangladesh lies hilly Meghalaya (‘the abode of clouds’). The state’s population predominantly comprises the Jaintia, Khasi and Garo tribal groups, who live in the eastern, central and western parts respectively. Geographically, Meghalaya is the first hill range that the rain baring monsoon clouds hit after crossing peninsular India and the Bay of Bengal.  Mawsynram and Cherrapunjee (Sohra) set on dramatic horseshoes of rocky cliffs receive some of the highest rainfall on earth, creating very impressive waterfalls and carving out some of Asia’s longest caves. Meghalaya’s tribal groups also maintain their matrilineal system, with property and names passed down from mother to daughter, and men moving in with their maternal in-laws after marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this tour we explore the best of the Khasi and Jaintia hills. Its hills, valleys, waterfalls, caves, quaint villages, sample its cuisine, interact with its wonderful inhabitants and more..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of the Mishmi Hills</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tours-mishmi-hills-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tours-mishmi-hills-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mishmi Hills is a southward extension of eastern most parts of the Great Himalayan Mountain Range - its high northern and eastern reaches touching China, whereas its southern parts fanning into the tropical forests of southwest China and Myanmar. On this tour we foray into the Dibang Valley district, named after the Dibang River - one of the key tributaries of the Brahmaputra. The Dibang originates in China and flows through the length of the valley in a north-south direction. Other river systems that flow through the area include the Ithun, Ason, Chipu, Aba, Iphi, Sisiri, Datung, and the Deopani River.
The Dibang Valley district is divided into Lower and Upper Dibang Valley. ). In between the start and the end, one will traverse across varied landscape, terrain, road conditions and meet the all important tribes of this region. From the Oil and Tea growing regions of Assam, the tropical forests of Namdapha and Kamlang to the cane and grasslands of the Acheso valley, everyday is a revelation. Interestingly during the entire ride you will cross territories of the Chakma, Singpho, Khamti, Miju Mishmi, Digaru Mishmi and finally the Idu Mishmi tribes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Western Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-western-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-western-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cycle tour of Arunachal Pradesh takes you all the way to the end of the road close to the tri-Juncture of Bhutan, Tibet and India. The setting of this ride is in western Arunachal Pradesh, the Buddhist belt of the state. This is one of the highest motorable routes of the eastern bit of the Himalayas, at places taking you to an altitude of 4200mts. The road condition though not at the best is still better than most parts of Arunachal Pradesh. The route takes you riding along the Bhutan border on little used roads. Slush, mud, broken roads steep inclines, long downhills, snow etc are all parts of this ride.The cycling phase covers between 300 to 650 Kms depending on the duration you choose, for most parts riding on little used backroads of this region historically known as the Monyul. Incidentally, in a rough manner we mirror the same route the Dalai Lama used in his exodus from Tibet in the year 1959.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Sikkim &amp; West Bengal</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-sikkim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-sikkim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sikkim, bordering Tibet in the north and northeast, Bhutan in the east, Nepal in the west, and West Bengal in the south is a mountanious state. Sikkim was its own mountain kingdom till 1975 and still retains a very distinctive personality. The meditative, mural-filled traditional monasteries of Tibetan Buddhism coexist with Hindu shrines of the ever-growing Nepali community, with both religions creating some astonishing latter-day megasculptures to adorn the skyline.Clean, green and &amp;lsquo;all organic&amp;rsquo; since 2016, Sikkim is mostly a maze of plunging, supersteep valleys thick with lush subtropical woodlands and rhododendron groves, rising in the north to the spectacular white-top peaks of the eastern Himalaya. When clouds clear, an ever-thrilling experience from many a ridge-top perch is spotting the world&amp;rsquo;s third-highest mountain, Khangchendzonga (8598m), on the northwestern dawn horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular tour takes you from Darjeeling in west bengal to the south and western districts to sikkim.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>