<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Walking on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/tags/walking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Walking on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/walking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Holiday in Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/walking-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/walking-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separating the Brahmaputra valley of Assam from the plains of Bangladesh lies hilly Meghalaya (‘the abode of clouds’). The state’s population predominantly comprises the Jaintia, Khasi and Garo tribal groups, who live in the eastern, central and western parts respectively. Geographically, Meghalaya is the first hill range that the rain baring monsoon clouds hit after crossing peninsular India and the Bay of Bengal.  Mawsynram and Cherrapunjee (Sohra) set on dramatic horseshoes of rocky cliffs receive some of the highest rainfall on earth, creating very impressive waterfalls and carving out some of Asia’s longest caves. Meghalaya’s tribal groups also maintain their matrilineal system, with property and names passed down from mother to daughter, and men moving in with their maternal in-laws after marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tour includes full day hikes and short walks to some of the best destination of the state. From historic trade routes to the natural wonders of bioengineering, sweeping panoramas of the Blangladeshi plains and its neighboring hills to deep valleys and canyons, through quaint remote villages and small local markets, we take you on a journey across this little known land.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Holiday in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/walking-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/walking-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arunachal Pradesh, ‘the dawn lit Mountains’ is the easternmost state of India. This tour is based in the eastern part of Arunachal Pradesh close to the Myanmar and Chinese frontiers, a maze of greenery and home to a vibrant mix of cultures. This is the land where three giant river valleys come down and meet the plains, hence giving birth to the mighty Brahmaputra. Home to the earliest tea producers of the subcontinent, some of the earliest oil finds of the world and a string of vibrant wildlife parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour includes a series of walks across these eastern most river valleys. This is a land of the Animist and Theravada Buddhist tribes of the state who are still very rooted in their culture and traditions. You will be walking through wildlife sanctuaries, camp next to pristine lakes, visit idellic villages, indulging in local cuisines and have authentic interactions with the people who live here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour is quite flexible and can be worked out around the duration that you have in hand. Do write in to us for the details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>