<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overland &amp; Motorcycle on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/categories/overland-motorcycle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overland &amp; Motorcycle on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/overland-motorcycle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overland Tour of Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Motorcycle / Overland tour takes you to Western Arunachal Pradesh which includes some of the highest motorable roads of the eastern Himalayas. This region is settled by the Tibetian Buddhism related tribes such as the Monpa, Sherdukpen and Brokpa. Historically this region has had close cultural and religious ties both to Bhutan and Tibet due to it being the tri-juncture between these three Kingdoms, infact it was under the protectorate of Tibet uptill 1945.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enroute you will get as high 4500mts. The Tawang Monastery, Sungatser Lake, Tse la pass, Gorsum Chorten and Nameri Wildlife Sanctuary are some of the highlights of this circuit. Riding conditions vary with canging road conditions and the time of travel. Good flat highways of Assam make way for a mix of good road conditions below the treeline and untarred jeepable tracks beyond the treeline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overland Tour of Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from Guwahati the capital of Assam, this motorcycle / overland tour takes you through little known secluded roads of Meghalaya. Entering Meghalaya in the western end we make our way to its far eastern hills, enroute traversing through varying conditions and basking in the vistas of the Meghalayan hills and the plains of Bangladesh while staying in charming locations all through settled by different tribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a land of plaetues, hills and deep river valleys. Richly endowned by nature with some of the deepest caves and tallest waterfalls of Asia. Almost every day you come across numerous waterfalls which depending on tour time of travel could vary from gushing frothy to a subtle glassy appearance. Depending on the duration you have the itinerary can include some cave exploration and canyoning in one of the longest caves of the world. We will take time to visit of the natural root bridges of the state including the most famous double decker bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route is quite flexible depending the duration you have in hand, level of involvement you want to put in or your techical ability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overland Tour of 4 states NE India </title>
      <link>/tours/motorcycle-tour-northeast-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/motorcycle-tour-northeast-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular ride takes us through the backroads of some of India’s easternmost states namely Arunachal Pradesh, Nagaland, Assam and Meghalaya. A rider’s delight, this route includes the dense forested hills of Nagaland, and Arunachal Pradesh, the tea oil rich regions of Assam and the wettest places on Earth at Meghalaya. Incidentally this region has one of the highest densities of ethnicities and languages in the whole of India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the tour we ride through territories of tribes such as the Nyshi, Apatani, Tagin, Galo, Adi, Idu Mishmi, Digaru Mishmi, Miju Mishmi, Singpho, Khamti, Konyak, Ao, Lotha, Angami, Karbi, Dimasa, Jaintia and Khasi to name a few. Infact every single day takes us through territories of different tribes, each tribe totally different from the previous. You will ride across swathes of lush tea plantations, some of the oldest oil fields on earth, some of the greatest wildlife sanctuaries of the sub-continent, the largest river island on earth, quaint and remote villages, orange orchards, unending forests, view some of the tallest waterfalls and visit some of the deepest caves of Asia among others. The loop starts and ends at Guwahati, which is the capital of Assam and the largest city among the seven states. The ride itself takes us through varying terrain, road conditions and vegetation, every single day bringing totally new and unique settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>