<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arunachal Pradesh on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/tags/arunachal-pradesh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Arunachal Pradesh on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/arunachal-pradesh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Activity holiday in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/multiactivity-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/multiactivity-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This multi-activity tour of eastern Arunachal Pradesh takes us on bicycles, rafts and on foot across the watershed area of the Brahmaputra River valley. This region situated at the foothills of the Mishmi hills the eastern flank to the Himalayan chain, is the land of the Animist and Theravada Buddhist tribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authentic interactions, local cuisine, history and lifestyle of the tribes etc are our focus here. The cycling phase takes us across territories of six different tribes where as the hiking phase takes us away from civilization into two different and unique wildlife sanctuaries. This multi-activity tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh also includes rafting on the Dibang and the Lohit rivers, the easternmost tributaries of the Brahmaputra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overland Tour of Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Motorcycle / Overland tour takes you to Western Arunachal Pradesh which includes some of the highest motorable roads of the eastern Himalayas. This region is settled by the Tibetian Buddhism related tribes such as the Monpa, Sherdukpen and Brokpa. Historically this region has had close cultural and religious ties both to Bhutan and Tibet due to it being the tri-juncture between these three Kingdoms, infact it was under the protectorate of Tibet uptill 1945.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enroute you will get as high 4500mts. The Tawang Monastery, Sungatser Lake, Tse la pass, Gorsum Chorten and Nameri Wildlife Sanctuary are some of the highlights of this circuit. Riding conditions vary with canging road conditions and the time of travel. Good flat highways of Assam make way for a mix of good road conditions below the treeline and untarred jeepable tracks beyond the treeline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-eastern-arunachal_pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-eastern-arunachal_pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cycle tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh (the eastern most state of India) takes you to the watershed of the mighty Brahmaputra River.  India’s wildest and least explored state, Arunachal (literally the ‘land of dawn-lit mountains’) rises abruptly from the Assam plains as a mass of densely forested and impossibly steep hills, culminating in snowcapped peaks along the Tibetan border. This state is home to 26 major tribes with over 100 sub-tribes and clans speaking some 50 odd dialects. Arunachal is perhaps the last sanctuary for India’s natural and anthropological heritage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular part of Arunachal Pradesh is where the three easternmost tributaries come together to form one of the mightiest river valleys of the world. Surrounded by the Himalayas and the Patkai Range on three sides and Brahmaputra valley on the other, this region is the home of numerous tribal cultures. Each one of these tribes are unique in their language, food, textile pattern, headgear, machetes etc, yet so distinct with strong Mongoloid features, tight knit society, and their nonchalant ease in and around the forests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Holiday in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/walking-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/walking-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arunachal Pradesh, ‘the dawn lit Mountains’ is the easternmost state of India. This tour is based in the eastern part of Arunachal Pradesh close to the Myanmar and Chinese frontiers, a maze of greenery and home to a vibrant mix of cultures. This is the land where three giant river valleys come down and meet the plains, hence giving birth to the mighty Brahmaputra. Home to the earliest tea producers of the subcontinent, some of the earliest oil finds of the world and a string of vibrant wildlife parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour includes a series of walks across these eastern most river valleys. This is a land of the Animist and Theravada Buddhist tribes of the state who are still very rooted in their culture and traditions. You will be walking through wildlife sanctuaries, camp next to pristine lakes, visit idellic villages, indulging in local cuisines and have authentic interactions with the people who live here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour is quite flexible and can be worked out around the duration that you have in hand. Do write in to us for the details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rainforest Trek in Eastern Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/rainforest-trek-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/rainforest-trek-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trekking holiday takes you to the Namdapha National Park located in eastern Arunachal Pradesh. Namdapha is one of the largest protected areas of Asia as well as the northernmost lowland evergreen rainforest of the world. We take you walking for 5 days through thick rain forest, grasslands and riverine areas of the national park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perched between the East Himalayan and the Indo-Burmese Biodiversity hotspots Namdapha is home to over 1000 species of plants, 425 avian species and over 90 species of mammals. This is also the only wildlife park to host four big cats in India, namely the Royal Bengal Tiger, Spotted Leopard, Snow Leopard and the Clouded Leopard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tour takes you far from the hustle bustle of daily life and deep into inarguably the wildest region of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family holiday in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/family-holiday-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/family-holiday-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This active family holiday of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh is set in some of the only flatlands of the state lying at the foothills of the Mishmi Hills (Himalayas eastern flank). Exploring around the Brahmaputra, Lohit and Dibang rivers. Rich plains have always given rise to more sophisticated and elaborate societies. This is the region where Hinduism, Theravada Buddhism and the Animist tribes meet and have coexisted for eons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the duration of this tour you will get an in-depth into this interesting regions wide mix of cultures, experience the lush environment and bio-diversity, indulge in some adventures and learn about the rich history of this little known corner of the sub-continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This holiday can be tailored to your family’s personal preferences, be it the range of activities, duration or accommodation options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of the Mishmi Hills</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tours-mishmi-hills-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tours-mishmi-hills-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mishmi Hills is a southward extension of eastern most parts of the Great Himalayan Mountain Range - its high northern and eastern reaches touching China, whereas its southern parts fanning into the tropical forests of southwest China and Myanmar. On this tour we foray into the Dibang Valley district, named after the Dibang River - one of the key tributaries of the Brahmaputra. The Dibang originates in China and flows through the length of the valley in a north-south direction. Other river systems that flow through the area include the Ithun, Ason, Chipu, Aba, Iphi, Sisiri, Datung, and the Deopani River.
The Dibang Valley district is divided into Lower and Upper Dibang Valley. ). In between the start and the end, one will traverse across varied landscape, terrain, road conditions and meet the all important tribes of this region. From the Oil and Tea growing regions of Assam, the tropical forests of Namdapha and Kamlang to the cane and grasslands of the Acheso valley, everyday is a revelation. Interestingly during the entire ride you will cross territories of the Chakma, Singpho, Khamti, Miju Mishmi, Digaru Mishmi and finally the Idu Mishmi tribes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Western Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-western-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-western-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cycle tour of Arunachal Pradesh takes you all the way to the end of the road close to the tri-Juncture of Bhutan, Tibet and India. The setting of this ride is in western Arunachal Pradesh, the Buddhist belt of the state. This is one of the highest motorable routes of the eastern bit of the Himalayas, at places taking you to an altitude of 4200mts. The road condition though not at the best is still better than most parts of Arunachal Pradesh. The route takes you riding along the Bhutan border on little used roads. Slush, mud, broken roads steep inclines, long downhills, snow etc are all parts of this ride.The cycling phase covers between 300 to 650 Kms depending on the duration you choose, for most parts riding on little used backroads of this region historically known as the Monyul. Incidentally, in a rough manner we mirror the same route the Dalai Lama used in his exodus from Tibet in the year 1959.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trekking in Western Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/trekking-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/trekking-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular trek is set in Western Arunachal Pradesh, in the states Buddhist belt close to the tri-junction between India, Tibet and Bhutan. This region is home to the Monpa, Sherdukpen and the Brokpa people. Starting from the township of Dirang, the trek takes you along the Bhutanese border via a region known for its high altitude lakes and rhodendrons while ending in the Sela Pass or Jang depending on the duration one chooses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This region is known as the eastern gateway to Tibet, an age old trading route between India, Bhutan and Tibet. In the duration of tour you will visit and experience some of the important places and aspects of this region such as spotting the River Dolphins of the Brahmaputra, visit the Tawang Monastry, Bum la pass and the orchidarium at Tipi among others. During the trek you will pass through remote settlements of the Brokpa (the yak and sheep herders) and the Monpa tribes , getting to interact and first hand window into their way of life. The trek starts from the sub-alpine forests at about 1500 mts and takes you up beyond the treeline reaching about 4200 mts. The trek takes of through forests of Rhodendrons in a typical Himalayan setting offering views of the high peaks of the Bhutan and Arunachal Himalayas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>