<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tours on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/tours/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tours on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/tours/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Active and Interactive Holidays in Northeast India</title>
      <link>/tours/active-holidays-northeast-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/active-holidays-northeast-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active-Northeast is an initiative of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nnejourneys.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;North by Northeast Journeys&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, one of the first to operate active tours in the region. For the past decade we have actively worked towards facilitating experiential travel which is Active, Interactive and Authentic in its truest form. Our tours of Northeast India include Cycling, Treks &amp;amp; Walks, Motorcycle &amp;amp; Overland, Multi-Activity, Family Adventures, Wildlife, Culture and Youth travel , all of which have local history, culture, interactions and the environment as their centerpiece. Although, most of our tours are activity based, our true focus lies on the people, the culture and environment of this region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Assam</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stretching 600km along the Brahmaputra River Valley, Assam is the largest and most accessible of the Northeast States. Well known for its national parks abounding in rhinoceroses, elephants, deer and primates (with respectable tiger numbers too), more than 3000sq km of lush tea plantations and a vibrant mix of cultures, it welcomes visitors with a subtly flavored cuisine and a hospitable population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cycle tour of Assam takes you on both the banks of central Brahmaputra Valley, giving you experiences of living in tea plantations, indulging in wildlife spotting, experiencing its rich cuisine while cycling through lush and pleasant surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>River Journey on the Brahmaputra</title>
      <link>/tours/river-trip-northeast-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/river-trip-northeast-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This river journey takes you to eastern Arunachal Pradesh and Upper Assam. Starting right from the mouth of the Brahmaputra Valley we meander down the Dibang river into the mighty Brahmaputra. This is a land surrounded by the mighty Himalayas and its lesser hill ranges on three sides and a myriad of rivers snaking west to form the only male river of India, The Brahmaputra. Over the duration of the tour you will raft and kayak down the swift flows of the Dibang to the more leisurely pace of the Brahmaputra, all the while having the options of Tubing, Body boarding, Snorkelling and Angling. Overnights will be spent camping in beautiful and secluded locations offering some of the most phenomenal sunsets. All meals will be freshly cooked and hot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflatable Kayaks (aka ‘Duckies’ or IKs) are perfect for adventure seekers. It offer the sensation of kayaking with better stability than a hard shell kayak. These boats are easy to paddle and manoeuvre, making them a great choice for novice to expert paddlers. Guides paddling their own inflatable kayaks will help teach you the basics and then lead you “follow-the-leader” style through the sections. If you should fall out: no problem; the guides will be right there to pick you up. It’s all part of the fun. So, the question is: are you a “do-it-yourselfer”? Looking for a little more adventure? Well here is your chance to sit above the flow and power your way down through the river on your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trip is not about big white water, it’s a more relaxed trip. Though in the first two days you will encounter a series of class 1 &amp;amp; 2 rapids, its generally all relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Holiday in Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/walking-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/walking-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separating the Brahmaputra valley of Assam from the plains of Bangladesh lies hilly Meghalaya (‘the abode of clouds’). The state’s population predominantly comprises the Jaintia, Khasi and Garo tribal groups, who live in the eastern, central and western parts respectively. Geographically, Meghalaya is the first hill range that the rain baring monsoon clouds hit after crossing peninsular India and the Bay of Bengal.  Mawsynram and Cherrapunjee (Sohra) set on dramatic horseshoes of rocky cliffs receive some of the highest rainfall on earth, creating very impressive waterfalls and carving out some of Asia’s longest caves. Meghalaya’s tribal groups also maintain their matrilineal system, with property and names passed down from mother to daughter, and men moving in with their maternal in-laws after marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tour includes full day hikes and short walks to some of the best destination of the state. From historic trade routes to the natural wonders of bioengineering, sweeping panoramas of the Blangladeshi plains and its neighboring hills to deep valleys and canyons, through quaint remote villages and small local markets, we take you on a journey across this little known land.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family holiday in Assam</title>
      <link>/tours/family-holiday-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/family-holiday-assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setting for this family holiday is the lush Brahmaputra valley of Assam. This is the physical heart of Northeastern India. A vast valley spread between the mighty Himalayas in the North and the lesser hills of Meghalaya and Nagaland in the South. Assam is the largest and most accessible of the Northeastern States. This fertile land is generally known for its rich wildlife parks, lush tea plantations and unique cultures. On this tour we will explore, experience and observe some of the best that this state has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This holiday can be tailored to your family’s personal preferences, be it the range of activities, duration or accommodation options. This trips can be guided, unguided , driver driven or selfdriven depending on your preference and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Activity holiday in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/multiactivity-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/multiactivity-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This multi-activity tour of eastern Arunachal Pradesh takes us on bicycles, rafts and on foot across the watershed area of the Brahmaputra River valley. This region situated at the foothills of the Mishmi hills the eastern flank to the Himalayan chain, is the land of the Animist and Theravada Buddhist tribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authentic interactions, local cuisine, history and lifestyle of the tribes etc are our focus here. The cycling phase takes us across territories of six different tribes where as the hiking phase takes us away from civilization into two different and unique wildlife sanctuaries. This multi-activity tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh also includes rafting on the Dibang and the Lohit rivers, the easternmost tributaries of the Brahmaputra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overland Tour of Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Motorcycle / Overland tour takes you to Western Arunachal Pradesh which includes some of the highest motorable roads of the eastern Himalayas. This region is settled by the Tibetian Buddhism related tribes such as the Monpa, Sherdukpen and Brokpa. Historically this region has had close cultural and religious ties both to Bhutan and Tibet due to it being the tri-juncture between these three Kingdoms, infact it was under the protectorate of Tibet uptill 1945.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enroute you will get as high 4500mts. The Tawang Monastery, Sungatser Lake, Tse la pass, Gorsum Chorten and Nameri Wildlife Sanctuary are some of the highlights of this circuit. Riding conditions vary with canging road conditions and the time of travel. Good flat highways of Assam make way for a mix of good road conditions below the treeline and untarred jeepable tracks beyond the treeline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-eastern-arunachal_pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-eastern-arunachal_pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cycle tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh (the eastern most state of India) takes you to the watershed of the mighty Brahmaputra River.  India’s wildest and least explored state, Arunachal (literally the ‘land of dawn-lit mountains’) rises abruptly from the Assam plains as a mass of densely forested and impossibly steep hills, culminating in snowcapped peaks along the Tibetan border. This state is home to 26 major tribes with over 100 sub-tribes and clans speaking some 50 odd dialects. Arunachal is perhaps the last sanctuary for India’s natural and anthropological heritage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular part of Arunachal Pradesh is where the three easternmost tributaries come together to form one of the mightiest river valleys of the world. Surrounded by the Himalayas and the Patkai Range on three sides and Brahmaputra valley on the other, this region is the home of numerous tribal cultures. Each one of these tribes are unique in their language, food, textile pattern, headgear, machetes etc, yet so distinct with strong Mongoloid features, tight knit society, and their nonchalant ease in and around the forests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Holiday in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/walking-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/walking-tour-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arunachal Pradesh, ‘the dawn lit Mountains’ is the easternmost state of India. This tour is based in the eastern part of Arunachal Pradesh close to the Myanmar and Chinese frontiers, a maze of greenery and home to a vibrant mix of cultures. This is the land where three giant river valleys come down and meet the plains, hence giving birth to the mighty Brahmaputra. Home to the earliest tea producers of the subcontinent, some of the earliest oil finds of the world and a string of vibrant wildlife parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour includes a series of walks across these eastern most river valleys. This is a land of the Animist and Theravada Buddhist tribes of the state who are still very rooted in their culture and traditions. You will be walking through wildlife sanctuaries, camp next to pristine lakes, visit idellic villages, indulging in local cuisines and have authentic interactions with the people who live here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour is quite flexible and can be worked out around the duration that you have in hand. Do write in to us for the details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family holiday Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/family-holiday-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/family-holiday-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This active holiday for the family is set in hilly Meghalaya. Meghalaya literally meaning the ‘Abode of clouds’ is one of the wettest places on earth during the monsoons. Cherrapunji and Mawsynram both in Meghalaya take their turn recording some of the heaviest rainfall on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this tour of Meghalaya you will be travelling through the west Khasi and neighbouring Jaintia hills overlooking the plains of Bangladesh. Deep forested valleys, gushing rivers, innumerable waterfalls, natural root bridges, archery competitions, village markets etc will be the common sights. Short hikes, water based activities,Ziplines, caves and waterfall visits are in the cards on this tour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This holiday can be tailored to your family’s personal preferences, be it the range of activities, duration or accommodation options. This trip can be driver driven or selfdriven depending on your preference and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Activity holiday in Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/multiactivity-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/multiactivity-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular Multi-activity tour takes us on bicycles and on foot across the Khasi and Jaintia Hills of Meghalaya. Due to its unique georgaphical location, it some of the highest rain fall on earth which in turn bestows this region with its amazing mix of forested valleys and grassland plateaus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cycling phase takes you across the beautiful landscape, whereas the hiking days take you through some of the best trails of the region, amongst which the famous living root bridges trail. Enroute we will picnic lunch in beautiful locations and swim in prestine pools while visitng waterfalls, caves and local archery competitions. During this multi activity tour of Meghalaya tour you will stay in quaint homestays, off the grid farms and small family run establishments. The tour will give you indepth and personal prospective of this land and its wonderful people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour is quite flexible, we can mould the entire proceeding looking at your preferences and abilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overland Tour of Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from Guwahati the capital of Assam, this motorcycle / overland tour takes you through little known secluded roads of Meghalaya. Entering Meghalaya in the western end we make our way to its far eastern hills, enroute traversing through varying conditions and basking in the vistas of the Meghalayan hills and the plains of Bangladesh while staying in charming locations all through settled by different tribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a land of plaetues, hills and deep river valleys. Richly endowned by nature with some of the deepest caves and tallest waterfalls of Asia. Almost every day you come across numerous waterfalls which depending on tour time of travel could vary from gushing frothy to a subtle glassy appearance. Depending on the duration you have the itinerary can include some cave exploration and canyoning in one of the longest caves of the world. We will take time to visit of the natural root bridges of the state including the most famous double decker bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route is quite flexible depending the duration you have in hand, level of involvement you want to put in or your techical ability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separating the Brahmaputra valley of Assam from the plains of Bangladesh lies hilly Meghalaya (‘the abode of clouds’). The state’s population predominantly comprises the Jaintia, Khasi and Garo tribal groups, who live in the eastern, central and western parts respectively. Geographically, Meghalaya is the first hill range that the rain baring monsoon clouds hit after crossing peninsular India and the Bay of Bengal.  Mawsynram and Cherrapunjee (Sohra) set on dramatic horseshoes of rocky cliffs receive some of the highest rainfall on earth, creating very impressive waterfalls and carving out some of Asia’s longest caves. Meghalaya’s tribal groups also maintain their matrilineal system, with property and names passed down from mother to daughter, and men moving in with their maternal in-laws after marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this tour we explore the best of the Khasi and Jaintia hills. Its hills, valleys, waterfalls, caves, quaint villages, sample its cuisine, interact with its wonderful inhabitants and more..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rainforest Trek in Eastern Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/rainforest-trek-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/rainforest-trek-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trekking holiday takes you to the Namdapha National Park located in eastern Arunachal Pradesh. Namdapha is one of the largest protected areas of Asia as well as the northernmost lowland evergreen rainforest of the world. We take you walking for 5 days through thick rain forest, grasslands and riverine areas of the national park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perched between the East Himalayan and the Indo-Burmese Biodiversity hotspots Namdapha is home to over 1000 species of plants, 425 avian species and over 90 species of mammals. This is also the only wildlife park to host four big cats in India, namely the Royal Bengal Tiger, Spotted Leopard, Snow Leopard and the Clouded Leopard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tour takes you far from the hustle bustle of daily life and deep into inarguably the wildest region of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family holiday in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/family-holiday-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/family-holiday-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This active family holiday of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh is set in some of the only flatlands of the state lying at the foothills of the Mishmi Hills (Himalayas eastern flank). Exploring around the Brahmaputra, Lohit and Dibang rivers. Rich plains have always given rise to more sophisticated and elaborate societies. This is the region where Hinduism, Theravada Buddhism and the Animist tribes meet and have coexisted for eons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the duration of this tour you will get an in-depth into this interesting regions wide mix of cultures, experience the lush environment and bio-diversity, indulge in some adventures and learn about the rich history of this little known corner of the sub-continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This holiday can be tailored to your family’s personal preferences, be it the range of activities, duration or accommodation options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overland Tour of 4 states NE India </title>
      <link>/tours/motorcycle-tour-northeast-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/motorcycle-tour-northeast-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular ride takes us through the backroads of some of India’s easternmost states namely Arunachal Pradesh, Nagaland, Assam and Meghalaya. A rider’s delight, this route includes the dense forested hills of Nagaland, and Arunachal Pradesh, the tea oil rich regions of Assam and the wettest places on Earth at Meghalaya. Incidentally this region has one of the highest densities of ethnicities and languages in the whole of India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the tour we ride through territories of tribes such as the Nyshi, Apatani, Tagin, Galo, Adi, Idu Mishmi, Digaru Mishmi, Miju Mishmi, Singpho, Khamti, Konyak, Ao, Lotha, Angami, Karbi, Dimasa, Jaintia and Khasi to name a few. Infact every single day takes us through territories of different tribes, each tribe totally different from the previous. You will ride across swathes of lush tea plantations, some of the oldest oil fields on earth, some of the greatest wildlife sanctuaries of the sub-continent, the largest river island on earth, quaint and remote villages, orange orchards, unending forests, view some of the tallest waterfalls and visit some of the deepest caves of Asia among others. The loop starts and ends at Guwahati, which is the capital of Assam and the largest city among the seven states. The ride itself takes us through varying terrain, road conditions and vegetation, every single day bringing totally new and unique settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of the Mishmi Hills</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tours-mishmi-hills-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tours-mishmi-hills-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mishmi Hills is a southward extension of eastern most parts of the Great Himalayan Mountain Range - its high northern and eastern reaches touching China, whereas its southern parts fanning into the tropical forests of southwest China and Myanmar. On this tour we foray into the Dibang Valley district, named after the Dibang River - one of the key tributaries of the Brahmaputra. The Dibang originates in China and flows through the length of the valley in a north-south direction. Other river systems that flow through the area include the Ithun, Ason, Chipu, Aba, Iphi, Sisiri, Datung, and the Deopani River.
The Dibang Valley district is divided into Lower and Upper Dibang Valley. ). In between the start and the end, one will traverse across varied landscape, terrain, road conditions and meet the all important tribes of this region. From the Oil and Tea growing regions of Assam, the tropical forests of Namdapha and Kamlang to the cane and grasslands of the Acheso valley, everyday is a revelation. Interestingly during the entire ride you will cross territories of the Chakma, Singpho, Khamti, Miju Mishmi, Digaru Mishmi and finally the Idu Mishmi tribes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Western Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-western-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-western-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cycle tour of Arunachal Pradesh takes you all the way to the end of the road close to the tri-Juncture of Bhutan, Tibet and India. The setting of this ride is in western Arunachal Pradesh, the Buddhist belt of the state. This is one of the highest motorable routes of the eastern bit of the Himalayas, at places taking you to an altitude of 4200mts. The road condition though not at the best is still better than most parts of Arunachal Pradesh. The route takes you riding along the Bhutan border on little used roads. Slush, mud, broken roads steep inclines, long downhills, snow etc are all parts of this ride.The cycling phase covers between 300 to 650 Kms depending on the duration you choose, for most parts riding on little used backroads of this region historically known as the Monyul. Incidentally, in a rough manner we mirror the same route the Dalai Lama used in his exodus from Tibet in the year 1959.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Sikkim &amp; West Bengal</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-sikkim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-sikkim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sikkim, bordering Tibet in the north and northeast, Bhutan in the east, Nepal in the west, and West Bengal in the south is a mountanious state. Sikkim was its own mountain kingdom till 1975 and still retains a very distinctive personality. The meditative, mural-filled traditional monasteries of Tibetan Buddhism coexist with Hindu shrines of the ever-growing Nepali community, with both religions creating some astonishing latter-day megasculptures to adorn the skyline.Clean, green and &amp;lsquo;all organic&amp;rsquo; since 2016, Sikkim is mostly a maze of plunging, supersteep valleys thick with lush subtropical woodlands and rhododendron groves, rising in the north to the spectacular white-top peaks of the eastern Himalaya. When clouds clear, an ever-thrilling experience from many a ridge-top perch is spotting the world&amp;rsquo;s third-highest mountain, Khangchendzonga (8598m), on the northwestern dawn horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular tour takes you from Darjeeling in west bengal to the south and western districts to sikkim.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trekking in Sikkim and Bengal</title>
      <link>/tours/trekking-sikkim-and-bengal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/trekking-sikkim-and-bengal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trek takes you to the hills of Sikkim and North Bengal, a mystical land of abundant natural beauty with verdant forests, quaint sub alpine villages and high towering mountains. Sikkim is home to the magnificant Kanchanjunga Massif, the third-highest mountain on earth. The pinnacle of this majestic mountain is perennially snowcapped and ever towering over the region like the deity that she is. The trek will take you across state and sometimes national borders, as we make our way south from the Barsey Rhodondren Sanctuary along the Nepalese frontier, walking the phenominal Singalila Ridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This region is perched between the giant plains of the Gangetic and Brahmaputra valleys and the high Himalayan massif. Barsey Rhododendron Sanctuary spans over the razor sharp Singalila Range which forms the border wall between India and Nepal. Ranging from an altitude of about 7000 to 14000 feet, the flora of the sanctuary ranges from broadleaf and coniferous forests to alpine meadows, but the queen of this sanctuary is the Rhodendron of which over 600 kinds can be found here itself. The route takes us from a starting altitude of about 2700 mts up to about 3750 mts. The Singalila ridge, which is about 50 kms long offers phenominal panoramas of the valleys of Nepal and Sikkim, and the high peaks of Himalayas especially the sights of 5 out of the 6 highest peaks on earth. The mornings and evenight offer spellbinding vistas, almost an amphitheatre where we are the spectators and the high peaks the protagonists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trek can be quite flexible in duration without losing its charms. Please write in to us with your ideal duration and we will get back with an appropriate itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trekking in Western Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/trekking-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/trekking-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular trek is set in Western Arunachal Pradesh, in the states Buddhist belt close to the tri-junction between India, Tibet and Bhutan. This region is home to the Monpa, Sherdukpen and the Brokpa people. Starting from the township of Dirang, the trek takes you along the Bhutanese border via a region known for its high altitude lakes and rhodendrons while ending in the Sela Pass or Jang depending on the duration one chooses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This region is known as the eastern gateway to Tibet, an age old trading route between India, Bhutan and Tibet. In the duration of tour you will visit and experience some of the important places and aspects of this region such as spotting the River Dolphins of the Brahmaputra, visit the Tawang Monastry, Bum la pass and the orchidarium at Tipi among others. During the trek you will pass through remote settlements of the Brokpa (the yak and sheep herders) and the Monpa tribes , getting to interact and first hand window into their way of life. The trek starts from the sub-alpine forests at about 1500 mts and takes you up beyond the treeline reaching about 4200 mts. The trek takes of through forests of Rhodendrons in a typical Himalayan setting offering views of the high peaks of the Bhutan and Arunachal Himalayas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Activity holiday in Assam</title>
      <link>/tours/multiactivity-tour-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/multiactivity-tour-assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This multi-activity tour takes us to the Brahmaputra valley of Assam. A lush strip of land sandwiched between the Himalayan landmass on the north and the lesser hills of Nagaland and Meghalaya in the south. The Brahmaputra valley is home to a multitude of ethinicities, a string of wildlife sanctuaries and the famous Assam tea among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this tour we will indulge in short day cycling and hiking forays. Explore the culture and cuisine of this land, embark on wildlife safari’s, live in and learn about life in a typical Assamese Tea Plantation, spot the endangered River Dolphins of the Brahmaputra, cycle around the largest river island of the world and much more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>