<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assam on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/tags/assam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assam on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/assam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Assam</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stretching 600km along the Brahmaputra River Valley, Assam is the largest and most accessible of the Northeast States. Well known for its national parks abounding in rhinoceroses, elephants, deer and primates (with respectable tiger numbers too), more than 3000sq km of lush tea plantations and a vibrant mix of cultures, it welcomes visitors with a subtly flavored cuisine and a hospitable population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cycle tour of Assam takes you on both the banks of central Brahmaputra Valley, giving you experiences of living in tea plantations, indulging in wildlife spotting, experiencing its rich cuisine while cycling through lush and pleasant surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family holiday in Assam</title>
      <link>/tours/family-holiday-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/family-holiday-assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setting for this family holiday is the lush Brahmaputra valley of Assam. This is the physical heart of Northeastern India. A vast valley spread between the mighty Himalayas in the North and the lesser hills of Meghalaya and Nagaland in the South. Assam is the largest and most accessible of the Northeastern States. This fertile land is generally known for its rich wildlife parks, lush tea plantations and unique cultures. On this tour we will explore, experience and observe some of the best that this state has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This holiday can be tailored to your family’s personal preferences, be it the range of activities, duration or accommodation options. This trips can be guided, unguided , driver driven or selfdriven depending on your preference and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Activity holiday in Assam</title>
      <link>/tours/multiactivity-tour-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/multiactivity-tour-assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This multi-activity tour takes us to the Brahmaputra valley of Assam. A lush strip of land sandwiched between the Himalayan landmass on the north and the lesser hills of Nagaland and Meghalaya in the south. The Brahmaputra valley is home to a multitude of ethinicities, a string of wildlife sanctuaries and the famous Assam tea among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this tour we will indulge in short day cycling and hiking forays. Explore the culture and cuisine of this land, embark on wildlife safari’s, live in and learn about life in a typical Assamese Tea Plantation, spot the endangered River Dolphins of the Brahmaputra, cycle around the largest river island of the world and much more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>