<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Easy to Moderate on Active Northeast</title>
    <link>/tags/easy-to-moderate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Easy to Moderate on Active Northeast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/easy-to-moderate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/tours/cycle-tour-eastern-arunachal_pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/cycle-tour-eastern-arunachal_pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cycle tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh (the eastern most state of India) takes you to the watershed of the mighty Brahmaputra River.  India’s wildest and least explored state, Arunachal (literally the ‘land of dawn-lit mountains’) rises abruptly from the Assam plains as a mass of densely forested and impossibly steep hills, culminating in snowcapped peaks along the Tibetan border. This state is home to 26 major tribes with over 100 sub-tribes and clans speaking some 50 odd dialects. Arunachal is perhaps the last sanctuary for India’s natural and anthropological heritage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular part of Arunachal Pradesh is where the three easternmost tributaries come together to form one of the mightiest river valleys of the world. Surrounded by the Himalayas and the Patkai Range on three sides and Brahmaputra valley on the other, this region is the home of numerous tribal cultures. Each one of these tribes are unique in their language, food, textile pattern, headgear, machetes etc, yet so distinct with strong Mongoloid features, tight knit society, and their nonchalant ease in and around the forests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overland Tour of Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tours/motorcycle-overland-tour-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from Guwahati the capital of Assam, this motorcycle / overland tour takes you through little known secluded roads of Meghalaya. Entering Meghalaya in the western end we make our way to its far eastern hills, enroute traversing through varying conditions and basking in the vistas of the Meghalayan hills and the plains of Bangladesh while staying in charming locations all through settled by different tribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a land of plaetues, hills and deep river valleys. Richly endowned by nature with some of the deepest caves and tallest waterfalls of Asia. Almost every day you come across numerous waterfalls which depending on tour time of travel could vary from gushing frothy to a subtle glassy appearance. Depending on the duration you have the itinerary can include some cave exploration and canyoning in one of the longest caves of the world. We will take time to visit of the natural root bridges of the state including the most famous double decker bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route is quite flexible depending the duration you have in hand, level of involvement you want to put in or your techical ability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>